Hi friends, my name is Sushil and you are watching
my channel Technical Knowledge Ba
Sushil. Today's blog is about how
we
can get our water connection installed under Delhi Jal Board in Delhi.
If you already have a
water connection in your house, even if you don't already have a water connection in your house,
then
how
can you apply for a new connection in your house?
Today we will see the complete process. For a new water
connection, first of all you have to come to the Delhi Jal
Board website. Its URL
is djb.gov.in. This is the government website.
After this, you have to come to Services. The
first option is Apply for New
Connection or Regularization. You have to
click on it. After this, you have to drag down and
come down. Then there is a close button,
you have to click on it. After this,
you are redirected to a new interface.
Now a form has opened in front of you,
Application Form for New Connection. Here
you have the complete form to apply for a new connection.
Now to fill this form,
you have to click on the first option.  There
is Z RO location, inside this you will see that
you have to select the location in which you live,
then
after this it is written Type of request, what
type of request do you want to give, Water
and Sewage Connection, Water Connection, Sewage
Connection, Regularization, now here water
connection, if like me, I already have a water connection in my house,
but
I want to apply for a second meter connection, then
I
will apply for water connection, friend,
if your house is brand new and you neither have a
water connection nor a sewerage
connection, then for this you will have to apply on water and
sewerage connection,
but I already have a water connection at my house,
I am applying for a second connection, then
you will have to click on water connection,
then second, are you
applying for a permanent connection, if you are doing a temporary connection,
then my
connection will
remain permanent, now here you have the option to upload the photo,
here you have an
edit option, you will click on it,
then your photo gets uploaded here
Then after this, the details of the person in whose name you
want to apply for the connection will
come here. Right now, I have it. For example,
our house is in the name of a joint owner,
but if you want to get it registered in your name, then
you will have to get
a notary paper made, in which
you will have to give NOC through a second party, then
you can get it registered in your name. So, the
name of the person in whose name you are applying for the connection will come, then
after this your father's name will come. Friend, if you are
applying for a government organization, then
you will have to tick here.
Otherwise, you have to leave the contact details
here. You have to fill in the email ID, mobile number and
office number. Friend,
under the mobile number and office number, you will have to
fill in different mobile numbers. The fifth option
is for Delhi Jal Board employees. If
any employee is from Delhi Jal Board, if you do
not fall under this, then you have to leave it.
There is a sixth option, property
address. Under the property address, you have to
fill in the complete address of that house as per the
documents. Now, as if you are
applying,  If yes, then you will have to fill any one document of that house
like the electricity
bill, I will fill my complete
address here because I have to show the
ownership according to my electricity bill,
so here
my name is on the electricity bill and the complete
address on it, I have to fill the same,
so you have to fill the complete address here,
if there is a landmark, you have to fill the landmark,
as soon as you fill the pin code,
then after this you will be asked to fill the locality here,
in assembly, you have to select the
assembly and in ward, you have to
select the ward, property and water
connection use details, now the property type has to be
filled here, what type of property is it, for example, if it is
our individual house, then
we will click on individual house,
what is the number of floors, you have to fill in whatever number of floors are there,
number of beds for
hospital and nursing home, it will be disabled
because it will be filled for hospital,
friend, here you have to write the plot area in square
meter, whatever is yours, you can fill that
net,
if you do not know how it will be converted into square meter,
what is the built up area,
you can do the same  You can also keep the built up area. Whether the
water connection category is commercial or
domestic, you have to select domestic here.
Friend, under water connection used by,
you will get many options like if
we are applying for domestic
then here you will see
residential, then you have to select residential here,
then here you have to
fill the bank details, after this you will see
whether you are applying for rain water harvesting,
otherwise you can skip it,
now here on the 10th serial number you will
see documents to be attached, here
you have to see which documents have to be attached, proof of identity, here
for identity you have bank passbook,
driving license, PAN card, passport,
ration card with applicant's photo, for
an ID card issued by any government
agency and here Aadhar card and water
identification card number i.e. voter ID,
here you can select any category of document,
I have Aadhar card,
I select my Aadhar card  I will do
Proof of Identity document,
you have to fill your Aadhaar number here,
then after this upload proof of
identity, here you have to upload the Aadhaar card
document which you have selected
and here
you have an icon of I, by clicking on it you
can see it is written please upload
valid image JPG JPEG GA PNG PDF the
file size should be within 5 MB,
then after this you have to
click on Upload Proof of Identity button, there is an
option of choose file, click on this,
then
you have to upload the Aadhaar card, then after this
ownership status, now here is owner,
occupied, tenant, legal heir or other, if
I am the owner now then I will
select owner, download self
declaration form here, here you have to
download the self declaration form, this is a
mandatory document, you can see this form, it is
written inside it
that I or V, if there is a single owner here then
he will fill it in his own name, if
joint  If he is the owner, then he will tick on V and then the
resident of which address he is applying for will be
filled and below you will see the
signature, if it is a single person then it will be single
signature, if it is a joint owner then it will be joint signature,
then the name of those joint persons will be there,
you will write the address of the property against which
you are applying for water connection
and the contact number, you can give one mobile number or
two also, so
after it is completely filled, you have to scan it,
then you have to upload this document by going to choose
file, then
your document gets uploaded here, then
after this, in property ownership, you have to
select the document,
what documents do you have right now, like I
have electricity bill in the name of the
applicant, like the electricity bill of
this property, this house, it is in my name,
so I have clicked on this option,
here you will get many categories of documents,
like
if you are the owner of this property, you have registered sale deed,
lease  If there is a deed or a registered GPA, then you
can give any document related to it if you have it. Here there is an option of
Will or NOC of the owner in favor of the
applicant, if you are giving Will or NOC, then
that will also be accepted. Right now I have an
electricity bill, so I select it
and this property ownership
document. Now here, if you have an
electricity bill, then you have to
fill the CA number here.
You have to pay attention to what is written here. Your electricity bill should be of the
last 3 months. You will
sign that document and upload it.
Similarly, if you have an Aadhar card,
you have to upload the Aadhar card, but
after taking out the photocopy, you have to sign and upload it. Similarly,
when all three of you take out the electricity bill of the
last 3 months, then on that side, if
you are a single owner, then the single owner will sign it.
If there is a joint owner,
he will also sign it. After this,
you have to upload the signed paper. Upload
property ownership document. There
is an I icon here, inside it you have to get a file size of 5 GB.
Yes friend, under Other,
if you have taken NOC from the owner,
then you will select NOC here,
then inside it, like there will be a notary, then
you have to fill the document number of the stem paper there and you have to
upload that document and
you have to upload that NAC copy, so friend,
we have seen that we have filled all the details here,
after filling all the details,
we have also uploaded the documents, then
you have to select Submitted By yourself,
then you have to upload your signature here, the
signature of the person in whose name the form is being filled will be uploaded here, then
you have to fill the captcha here,
after this you have to click on the check box of I Agree,
then click on the preview button,
after cross checking all the details, if everything is
found correct, then after this you have to
click on the submit button, so friend,
we have seen that our form has been submitted,
here you can see the name of the applicant,
application type and
application reference number and what is the built up area
in square meters and date of  On
which date was the submission made, then
after this there is download feed application form
and acknowledgement received, here you have to
download the acknowledgement received first, then
after this you have to save
it by clicking on download feed application form,
so friend we
saw how we can
apply for new water connection in Delhi,
so thank you friend for watching
my channel, thank you